[
    {
        "passage": [
            "When Nancy was about seven, a travelling circus came to her town and she still remembers what a strong impression it made on her. She loved all the characters so she dreamt of running away to join them. She seriously considered all the possibilities: lion tamer, elephant handler, acrobat, trapeze artist, but in the end she decided to be a clown. She remembers spending long hours at her mother’s dressing table, putting on make-up to create a clown’s face and then making faces in front of the mirror. Unfortunately, she couldn’t run away to join the circus."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What happened when Nancy was seven years old?",
                "A": "She made an impression on a travelling circus.",
                "B": "She saw a travelling circus in her town.",
                "C": "She joined a travelling circus to run away.",
                "D": "She became a clown for a travelling circus.",
                "answer": "She saw a travelling circus in her town."
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word “it” in line 2 refer to?",
                "A": "her town",
                "B": "a strong impression",
                "C": "a travelling circus",
                "D": "a character",
                "answer": "a travelling circus"
            },
            {
                "question": "Why did Nancy want to join the circus?",
                "A": "Because she could travel out of her town.",
                "B": "Because she loved to act as a clown.",
                "C": "Because she loved all the characters.",
                "D": "Because she was a serious performer.",
                "answer": "Because she loved all the characters."
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the word “possibilities” in line 3 closest in meaning to?",
                "A": "choices",
                "B": "chances",
                "C": "prospects",
                "D": "threats",
                "answer": "choices"
            },
            {
                "question": "What did Nancy finally choose to become?",
                "A": "An elephant handler",
                "B": "A lion tamer",
                "C": "A trapeze artist",
                "D": "A clown",
                "answer": "A clown"
            },
            {
                "question": "Why did Nany spend long hours at her mother’s dressing table?",
                "A": "To remove the make-up",
                "B": "To create a clown costume",
                "C": "To design a portrait",
                "D": "To wear make-up",
                "answer": "To create a clown costume"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "passage": [
            "John plays the piano. He plays it very well. He started playing the piano when he was six years old. After a year, he played better and better. Now he is 13 years old. He is very good. He won one piano contest after another. A famous piano teacher heard him play the piano. The teacher said, “I want to bring you to New York. I will teach you how to be even better. I will teach you how to be the best piano player in the whole world.” He didn’t like that idea. He wanted to stay at home. He wanted to stay with his parents and his friends. His parents wanted him to go. They said they would visit him in New York every weekend."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "How did John play the piano?",
                "A": "Very healthily",
                "B": "Very brilliantly",
                "C": "Very intelligently",
                "D": "Very modestly",
                "answer": "Very brilliantly"
            },
            {
                "question": "When did John begin playing the piano?",
                "A": "When he was five.",
                "B": "When he was four.",
                "C": "When he was six.",
                "D": "When he was seven",
                "answer": "When he was six."
            },
            {
                "question": "How old is John now according to the passage?",
                "A": "Seven",
                "B": "Six",
                "C": "Thirteen",
                "D": "Eighteen",
                "answer": "Thirteen"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following best paraphrases this sentence: “He won one piano contest after another”?",
                "A": "He was the winner of many piano contests.",
                "B": "He won all of the piano contests.",
                "C": "He only won one piano contest.",
                "D": "He was better at one piano contest then at the other.",
                "answer": "He was the winner of many piano contests."
            },
            {
                "question": "Who wanted to bring John to New York?",
                "A": "His piano teacher",
                "B": "A person who met him at a piano contest.",
                "C": "His parents",
                "D": "A piano teacher hearing him play the piano.",
                "answer": "A piano teacher hearing him play the piano."
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the phrase “that idea” refer to?",
                "A": "That he would travel to New York and be taught to be the best.",
                "B": "That he should have learnt to be the best among piano players.",
                "C": "That someone would teach him how to play the piano better.",
                "D": "That playing the piano in New York would change his world.",
                "answer": "That he would travel to New York and be taught to be the best."
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is true about John?",
                "A": "He became locally famous for playing the piano as a child.",
                "B": "He took part in more than one piano contest when he was 13.",
                "C": "He refused to go to New York to improve his piano skills.",
                "D": "He was forced by his parents to play the piano in New York.",
                "answer": "He was forced by his parents to play the piano in New York."
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the passage mainly about?",
                "A": "A famous piano player",
                "B": "A boy who plays the piano",
                "C": "The development of a piano player",
                "D": "Benefits of playing the piano",
                "answer": "A boy who plays the piano"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "passage": [
            "Television is one of man’s most important advances in communication. It brings images and sounds from around the world into millions of homes. A person with a TV set can sit in this house and watch the president make a speech or visit a foreign country on television. Viewers can see and learn about people, places and things in far-off lands. In addition to all those tings, TV brings its viewers a steady stream of programs which are designed to entertain. In fact, TV is very useful for our spiritual life, and it is always a cheap source of entertainment."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is true about television?",
                "A": "It makes people’s lives more useful.",
                "B": "It connects millions of homes worldwide.",
                "C": "It provides a lot of benefits to people.",
                "D": "It inspires people to travel far away.",
                "answer": "It provides a lot of benefits to people."
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word “It” in line 1 refer to?",
                "A": "Communication",
                "B": "Advance",
                "C": "The world",
                "D": "Television",
                "answer": "Television"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT mentioned as an advantage of television?",
                "A": "A source of entertainment",
                "B": "A source of knowledge",
                "C": "A source of spiritual practices",
                "D": "A source of news",
                "answer": "A source of spiritual practices"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the word “steady” closest in meaning to?",
                "A": "unchanging",
                "B": "constant",
                "C": "balanced",
                "D": "secured",
                "answer": "constant"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the main purpose of the passage?",
                "A": "To encourage people to buy TV sets",
                "B": "To stress the importance of people’s mental lives",
                "C": "To prove how significant television is",
                "D": "To introduce a new way of virtual travelling",
                "answer": "To prove how significant television is"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "passage": [
            "Marie Curie was born in 1867. She is one of the greatest scientists ever to have lived. She was a pioneer in the field of radioactivity and discovered the chemical elements radium and polonium. Curie is the only person ever to win two Nobel Prizes in two different sciences. Other achievements include being the first female professor at the University of Paris.",
            "Curie was born in Warsaw, Poland. Her father was a maths and physics teacher and was a big influence on Marie’s early education. From an early age, Marie was an exceptional student with an amazing memory. She often went without food and sleep to study. Her brilliant mind led her to Paris to study and conduct her research.",
            "She met her future husband Pierre Curie at the university. He considered Marie to be a genius and instantly wanted to work with her. They got married and spent most of their time together in their laboratory studying radioactive materials. Their research led to the discovery of radium, for which they were honoured with the Nobel Prize for Physics in 1903."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is true about Marie Curie?",
                "A": "She was born in the 19th century.",
                "B": "She was the greatest chemist of her era.",
                "C": "She studied radioactivity because of her husband.",
                "D": "She was the first female professor ever.",
                "answer": "She was born in the 19th century."
            },
            {
                "question": "What did Marie find from her research?",
                "A": "Radioactive elements",
                "B": "Some chemical reactions",
                "C": "Radium’s usefulness in medicine",
                "D": "How to produce polonium from radium",
                "answer": "Radioactive elements"
            },
            {
                "question": "How many Nobel Prizes did Marie win?",
                "A": "One",
                "B": "Two",
                "C": "Three",
                "D": "Four",
                "answer": "Two"
            },
            {
                "question": "Where was Marie born?",
                "A": "Paris",
                "B": "Wattrelos",
                "C": "Warsaw",
                "D": "Poznan",
                "answer": "Warsaw"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who had an impact on Marie’s early education?",
                "A": "Her grandmother",
                "B": "Her grandfather",
                "C": "Her mother",
                "D": "Her father",
                "answer": "Her mother"
            },
            {
                "question": "What did Marie often do when she was young?",
                "A": "She often learnt from exceptional students.",
                "B": "She often studied without eating or sleeping.",
                "C": "She often went to Paris to conduct research.",
                "D": "She often made use of her memory in research.",
                "answer": "She often studied without eating or sleeping."
            },
            {
                "question": "Why did Marie’s husband want to work with her before their marriage?",
                "A": "Because he adored her ability to work hard.",
                "B": "Because she showed a natural ability in science.",
                "C": "Because he wanted to learn from her discovery.",
                "D": "Because she instantly responded to his curiosity.",
                "answer": "Because she showed a natural ability in science."
            },
            {
                "question": "Where did Marie and her husband spend most their time after their marriage?",
                "A": "In leading universities",
                "B": "In their house",
                "C": "In their offices",
                "D": "In their laboratory",
                "answer": "In their laboratory"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about the Nobel Prize of Physics mentioned in the passage?",
                "A": "It was awarded in 1903.",
                "B": "It was for a great chemical discovery.",
                "C": "It was granted to a couple.",
                "D": "It was given at the University of Paris.",
                "answer": "It was given at the University of Paris."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "passage": [
            "Saturday morning meant one thing for Susan – doing the laundry. She hated doing the laundry. Unenthusiastically, she took the pillow cases off all the pillows. Then she removed the fitted sheet from the mattress. She took the towel off the towel bar in the bathroom. She grabbed a couple of dirty dish towels out of the kitchen, and looked all around her apartment for anything else that needed washing.",
            "In the corner of her living room, a can of coins sat on top of the file cabinet. She fished out seven quarters. She opened the cabinet under her kitchen sink and grabbed a plastic bottle of liquid detergent.",
            "Finally, she set her electronic timer for 35 minutes. The timer would remind her that the washing was done, and that it was time to go back downstairs and put the clothes into the dryer for 40 minutes. Without the timer, Susan would completely forget to check her clothes.",
            "Susan carried the laundry basket downstairs. How happy she would be when laundry was done for this week. As she approached the laundry room, she heard a familiar sound. The sound was the washer washing and the dryer drying. One of her neighbors had got there before her. Muttering, Susan took her basket back upstairs."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the word “Unenthusiastically” in line 2 closest meaning to?",
                "A": "Reluctantly",
                "B": "Joyfully",
                "C": "Hopelessly",
                "D": "Patiently",
                "answer": "Reluctantly"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following did Susan do before the other?",
                "A": "She looked all around her apartment for anything else.",
                "B": "She grabbed some dirty dish towels out of the kitchen.",
                "C": "She removed the fitted sheet from the mattress.",
                "D": "She opened the cabinet under her kitchen sink.",
                "answer": "She removed the fitted sheet from the mattress."
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following did NOT need washing?",
                "A": "The fitted sheet",
                "B": "The towel bar",
                "C": "The dish towels",
                "D": "The pillow cases",
                "answer": "The towel bar"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the word grabbed in line 3 closest meaning to?",
                "A": "received",
                "B": "obtained",
                "C": "collected",
                "D": "took",
                "answer": "collected"
            },
            {
                "question": "How long does it take to dry the laundry?",
                "A": "20 minutes",
                "B": "30 minutes",
                "C": "40 minutes",
                "D": "50 minutes",
                "answer": "40 minutes"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is true about Susan?",
                "A": "She was paid to do the laundry on Saturday mornings.",
                "B": "She had no interest in doing the laundry herself.",
                "C": "She had the laundry done by a neighbor once a week.",
                "D": "She shared the liquid detergent with heir neighbors.",
                "answer": "She had no interest in doing the laundry herself."
            },
            {
                "question": "Why was Susan happy?",
                "A": "Because she heard a familiar sound in the laundry room.",
                "B": "Because she got to the laundry room before her neighbors.",
                "C": "Because she was carrying her laundry basket downstairs.",
                "D": "Because she thought she would soon finish doing the laundry.",
                "answer": "Because she thought she would soon finish doing the laundry."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "passage": [
            "A famous poet came on a visit to a lady who always said that she was fond of literature and especially of poetry. When they sat down to tea, the poet wondered whether she had received the little book of poems he had sent her. With a charming smile, the lady said to him that the poems were splendid and she would like to read some from the book, but she could not remember where she had put it. While her little daughter did not seem to care about it, her little son was ready with the answer: “Under the leg of the table, Mama, to make it steady.”"
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is true about the famous poet mentioned in the passage?",
                "A": "He came to a lady’s house.",
                "B": "He was fond of a lady’s poems.",
                "C": "He drank tea with a lady’s son.",
                "D": "He wondered about a lady’s poems.",
                "answer": "He came to a lady’s house."
            },
            {
                "question": "How was the lady’s smile?",
                "A": "Encouraging",
                "B": "Inviting",
                "C": "Attractive",
                "D": "Supportive",
                "answer": "Attractive"
            },
            {
                "question": "What did the lady think of the poems in the book?",
                "A": "Sparking",
                "B": "Impressive",
                "C": "Practical",
                "D": "Dreamy",
                "answer": "Impressive"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT mentioned about the lady?",
                "A": "She was keen on literature.",
                "B": "She was given a book of poems.",
                "C": "She already read the whole book.",
                "D": "She wanted to read the book of poem.",
                "answer": "She already read the whole book."
            },
            {
                "question": "Where did the lady put the book of poems?",
                "A": "Near the tea pot",
                "B": "In her bedroom",
                "C": "Under the leg of the table",
                "D": "On the table",
                "answer": "Under the leg of the table"
            },
            {
                "question": "Who told the lady about where she put the book of poems?",
                "A": "The poet",
                "B": "Her son",
                "C": "Her daughter",
                "D": "No one",
                "answer": "Her son"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the word “it” in line 5 refer to?",
                "A": "the book",
                "B": "the answer",
                "C": "the leg",
                "D": "the table",
                "answer": "the table"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "passage": [
            "Today English is one of the major languages in the world. However, in Shakespeare’s time, only a few million people spoke English. In fact, this language was not thought to be very important by the other nations of Europe, and it was unknown to the rest of the world.",
            "English has become a world language because of its establishment as a mother tongue outside England, in all of the continents of the world. This exporting of English began in the seventeenth century, with the first settlements in North America. Above all, it is the great growth of population in the United States, assisted by massive immigration in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries, that has given the English language its present standing in the world.",
            "People who speak English fall into one of three groups: those who have learned it as their native language; those who have learned it as a second language in a society that is mainly bilingual; and those who are forced to use it for a practical purpose: administrative, professional, or educational. One person in seven of the world’s entire population belongs to one of these three groups. Incredibly enough, 75% of the world’s mails and 60% of the world’s telephone calls are in English."
        ],
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is true about English in Shakespeare’s time?",
                "A": "It was a common language in most European countries.",
                "B": "It was popularly used inside and outside England.",
                "C": "It was spoken by a small number of people worldwide.",
                "D": "It was thought to be significant for global communication.",
                "answer": "It was spoken by a small number of people worldwide."
            },
            {
                "question": "Why has English become a world language?",
                "A": "Because it is the first language of many people throughout the world.",
                "B": "Because it is attractive to mothers on every continent.",
                "C": "Because the population using it in England has increased.",
                "D": "Because more English people have settled in North America.",
                "answer": "Because it is the first language of many people throughout the world."
            },
            {
                "question": "Where was English exported to first?",
                "A": "South America",
                "B": "West America",
                "C": "North America",
                "D": "East America",
                "answer": "North America"
            },
            {
                "question": "When was English first exported to places outside of England?",
                "A": "In the sixteenth century",
                "B": "In the seventeenth century",
                "C": "In the eighteenth century",
                "D": "In the nineteenth century",
                "answer": "n the seventeenth century"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is true according to the passage?",
                "A": "Two thirds of the global population use English as their first language.",
                "B": "The massive immigration helped to spread English across the world.",
                "C": "The United States encouraged its people to use more English.",
                "D": "English has been used as a world language since it was exported to North America.",
                "answer": "The massive immigration helped to spread English across the world."
            },
            {
                "question": "How many groups of people speaking English are mentioned?",
                "A": "Two",
                "B": "Three",
                "C": "Four",
                "D": "Five",
                "answer": "Three"
            },
            {
                "question": "According to the passage, for which purposes are people made to use English?",
                "A": "Communicative, administrative, and educational purposes",
                "B": "Administrative, professional, and communicative purposes",
                "C": "Professional, communicative, and educational purposes",
                "D": "Administrative, professional, and educational purposes",
                "answer": "Administrative, professional, and educational purposes"
            },
            {
                "question": "Why does the author mention the percentage of the world’s  mails and telephone calls in English?",
                "A": "To illustrate the purposes for using English",
                "B": "To encourage the use of mails and telephone calls",
                "C": "To stress the popularity of English in the world",
                "D": "To compare the use of mails and telephone calls",
                "answer": "To stress the popularity of English in the world"
            }
        ]
    }
]